Contact

rntrauma33@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kellyfranchetti-rn-ccrn-cen-66343550 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Clinical Trials
Clinical Development
CRO

Kelly Franchetti RN,CCRN,CEN

Vice President, Global Head Patient Insights and Engagement, Executive Principal - ACC

Chalfont, Pennsylvania

Summary

Highly experienced registered nurse who continues to spend time with patients directly. I have more than twenty five years of experience in obtaining and understanding the patient and caregiver experience as well as developing strong relationships with advocacy groups on a global scale. I understand how to engage with patients, caregivers and advocacy to obtain robust insights to positively affect protocol development, patient recruitment and retention strategies, shared decision making tools as well as adherence modeling. I work to ensure that the patient voice is incorporated across the entire lifecycle of drug development from early phase 1/2 all the way through to commercialization. We have developed proven methodologies that truly and effectively engage with any patient population to not only meet every business need of our clients but to empower the patient and their surrounding ecosystem of influencers.

Experience

ICON plc

Vice President, Global Head Patient Insights and Engagement July 2014 - Present (6 years 1 month)

Greater Philadelphia Area

Mapi Group

Vice President, Global Patient Insights and Engagement July 2014 - Present (6 years 1 month)

Greater Philadelphia Area

Develop, maintain and continually improve services, tools and methods in support of Mapi's Real World Evidence patient-centered solution offerings on a global scale with a special emphasis on recruitment and retention of patients for late phase projects.

Help to drive and support the continual development of Mapi's company-wide strategy around patient recruitment and engagement.

Internal consultant/SME relating to the continuum of patient contact/ engagement from pre-study onward.

inVentiv Health
VP Clinical Insights & Strategy
March 2013 - June 2014 (1 year 4 months)

ePharmaSolutions
Associate Director Business Development
July 2012 - March 2013 (9 months)

Education

Drexel University's College of Nursing and Health Professions Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1989 - 1993)